side welcome to concept and coding and
today in the part two of the jpa we are
going to do some very very important
topics of it but before starting that if
you have not watched the part one which
is a fundamental then I would suggest
you that if you don't know about spring
boot uh jdbc then watch out this video
and I have shared the link in the
description section so let's start
without wasting any time in the part one
I have covered the jdbc now let's start
with the OM so if you have watched the
part one then you remember this diagram
where the application your application
logic right there we were directly
connecting with the jdbc right but
now in the omm this Frameworks comes in
mid between your application and the
jdbc so in jdbc we directly work with
SQL now because of the orm framework
which is object relational
mapping this framework allow your
application to work with the object
itself and still you can manage your DB
you don't have to uh know SQL or you
have to work with
SQL so in the orm framework there are
two components jpa and let's say in for
now hibernate jpa is nothing you can say
that provides an interface okay and
hibernate open jpa or Eclipse link these
are nothing but an implementation of jpa
okay so this is the
default which spring boot uses for the
implementation of jpa but if you want to
use different uh definitely you can
override it right you can provide that
you want to use open jpa or Eclipse link
uh instead of hibernate as the
implementation of jpa okay so we have to
understand the architecture of jpa to
clearly see what actually happens
underline okay
so om as I told you it act as a bridge
between Java object and database table
unlike jdbc where we have to work with
SQL with this we can interact with the
database using Java objects itself okay
so I think definition is clear now
before I jump into this
architecture of jpa let's first see one
happy flow first like the complete what
all things required to do a setup of the
jpa and we will run one very simple
program and because why this is required
now because once we have seen that right
what all things are required to run one
simple uh program using jpa and then
when we internally go to individual
component we get more in light okay yes
this is how it was uh
working the first thing you definitely
need is dependency so here the first
thing we have to add a dependency in our
pom.xml and when you write this jpa
dependency internally by default it
brings hibernate dependency also so you
don't have to uh
specifically add the hybernate
dependency here this bring it with
it the second part as I told in the
first video itself you have seen it the
database connection properties we have
to provide here like what is the
database URL and this is the DB name
what is the driver username and password
we already know each of this in depth
like in the previous section so we have
to provide the application properties so
that's also we have done what is the
third so the third is this one you have
to create one entity this is the New
Concept right here in the
jpa entity we will see in depth in the
future video but for now I will tell you
what entity is entity considered this
it's a Java class entity is a Java class
which is equivalent to a table in
DB okay so here if you see that I what
DB I have created user DB so I have user
DB inside this user DB there can be
multiple
tables okay there can be multiple tables
so one tables which I created is user
table okay so this is my user table user
details table inside this user DB and
this
table has these columns so these are the
the fields of this class will be
considered as a column for the table ID
name and email this ID I made as a at
theate ID which is I am considering as a
primary key and that would be
autogenerated and whenever you create a
new instance of it let's say new user
details means you are creating a row
inside a table so what is the table user
details user details is your table and
what are the column
ID name email so these are the column
and whenever you are creating a new
instance means you are creating a new
row
okay so this is the third step you have
created so first is form second is
application. properties third is you
define all the
entities now this is the fourth which
you required that is
repository okay so here if you say that
I have have created a user detail
repository which is an interface and I
have extended the jpa repositories so
jpa repository we will see later that it
provide an
interface and
expose
API
API to
insert get
modify Etc okay so this is just a JPM uh
repository already has so many apis
where you can do insert insert some user
object get the user details modify it
okay so we have since this is a generic
class jpa is a like a generic class we
have to tell like on which object it has
to work with so that's why we have
created one
repository class and I have created an
interface user detail Repository
and when I extended it I provided that
okay this is for this
entity okay
so this for for each entity generally we
create one separate repository class
okay and in the jpa repository we
provide that a specific object a
specific entity class object that and
why this separate class is also required
is sometime we have to write our own
queries like uh jpql jql sometime we
call as jql Java persistence query
language right not SQL jql or if you're
using hibernate hql hiet query language
we have to Define our own query we don't
use to we don't want to use this
predefined method insert get modified we
want to write our own query then you can
write here okay so you can use this
specific entity repository class okay so
this is the fourth thing you required
now that's Sol
only this one you have added the
dependency added the application
properties created an entity and created
a repository for this you are
done now I all I have done is created a
supported classes so one I have created
a controller class and I have just
exposed one API / test hyph jpa so that
when from Postman I hit I get a control
over here nothing much and inside that
what I am doing is I am
first doing save user okay so I have
created one service class because
controller talk to service and service
talks to repository so that's generally
the flow in springboard right so I am
just created a service class in that one
I am connecting with the
repository and in the service class I
have two method save user and get all
user so from the controller when I am
calling save user it is calling this
method and ultimately which calls the
user detail
repository user detail
repository do save so ultimately which
save method will call which is present
into the jpa
repository right so it's already provide
us uh default methods which performs the
operation and I've just provided the
object
okay similarly what after that what I'm
doing get all users so it will try to
fetch all the users so it will invoke
this method and internally it's calling
find all so see find all is also present
inside jpa repository so I don't have to
write it so find all is also there and
I'm utilizing it if you have any
specific query which is not present into
the JP repository then you can write it
here but currently for a save and find
all we are using
it okay and now if I hit the API which
one / API SL test hyph jpa this API I
hit the control will come here so first
it will save the user this detail XY Z
name is XY Z and the email is XYZ at
concept encoding.com and then it will
fetch it and return it and ultimately
output you will see
here okay we can also check the DB also
so if you want to check the the DB So
currently let's say if you are using
MySQL then you will start the server of
the my SQL right then you know the path
what is the path but if you are using S2
which is in memory okay then for that
also we can view the console so for that
these two properties we have to add into
the application do properties spring.
s2. console enable true console I have
to enable and what is the path for the
console I have given S2
console so if you type
this into the Chrome uh HTTP what is
your server running on and this is the
path which we have given S2
console your console will open and there
you can see the details so here if you
see what is the table I have created
user detail what is the DB I created
user DB
so here user DB user details and we have
created when you hit this API you have
created one row and then you are
fetching it so here you see one row is
created okay so we can see that also
Let's see we will do all these things
set up then I will go to architecture so
that
okay so here first pom.xml let's open
the application. properties uh not uh
pom.xml
here if you see that I have already
added the dependency so dependency is
there first point is okay then second
application. properties I have provided
the database connection here right how
we used to provide in jdbc and I have
provided the console for the S2 and even
I have written the that whatever the
queries internally are running I want to
show it generally in production we don't
do this all this it's just for
development
testing so whatever the internally
hibernate is running the queries I want
to see so that's why I put spring. jpa
show SQL true and the hibernate format
SQL like hibernate has it own format to
show I made it true okay so this is our
second point is completed application.
properties is done then user
details so here if you see that I have
created a
entity user
details three columns it has ID name and
email and ID I marked as primary key and
its value would be automatic
generated okay the default Constructor
is mandatory for this one and uh a pojo
uh it's a normal pojo getter and Setter
so third is also done then I have
created Repository
here if you see I have just created a
repository for this user detail if any
specific a specific query I want to
write I can write it here but JP already
provides so many things like save flush
we will see one by one like what all
things required like find all get by ID
get one so if anything you already want
to reuse you can reuse
it okay and after that that we have a
service
layer in service layer I am just uh
including the dependency of
repository and I have created one method
save user which is calling this save
method and I have one find by ID it is
calling this find by ID right I am not
doing find all I am just doing find by
ID I want only one so this method is
also present okay and then ultimately to
bring the control so don't go that why I
am using get if I am doing save this is
just for testing that control comes here
so that we can test our flow so I
created One controller I have included
the dependency of service because
controller always talk to service not
directly to
repository so here first I have created
one instance of user detail when I said
that instance means we are trying to
create one row okay so I created one
instance of user detail I am now saving
it okay and then I am trying to fetch it
and return the user
detail so let's start the
server so here if you see first thing my
server is started what you see
here it is first dropping if exist this
table okay and then it is creating this
table so I told you that we are using S2
in memory DB so whenever you start an
application existing data is Dro and the
new tables are
created so now let's also so till now
application is started I not hitting the
query here now here if you see I am
hitting this what is the path for the
console we have given S2 hyen console
right and this is on which my
application server is running so I am
hitting this
one so this page will open okay so you
have to connect uh generic S2 server yes
we are connect to generic one the driver
the URL which you are connecting to DB
yeah this is the URL we provided in the
application. properties you can check
right this is the
URL okay and the username is saay
password is empty
connect so now here if you see that one
table is there user unor details so one
table is created now if you run it
currently it does it has any data no no
data so now we let's hit one query test
jpa right so let's HT
it so we got the output and let's see
the
console it did an
insert it created an insert and if you
check this now run it again one row
comes okay
there you might be asking right herey sh
I see only insert but in the controller
we are first inserting it and then we
are doing fine but why there is no
select query it because of caching uh
hibernate do first level of caching that
we will see later I will go in depth of
that one that is very very important
topic
but internally it does
fetch okay so now we know what all
things are required and how uh jpa basic
save and fetch is working but that is
not sufficient like we have to know
indepth of
it that's where the things get
complicated and interesting
both so here let's start with the jpa
architecture or let's say that what are
the components involved behind the
scene the first thing is persistence
unit okay
so here if you see persistence unit is
what persistence unit is where we
provide our
configurations like DB
connections okay what is the dialect we
want to
use what is the dialect okay what is the
driver Etc we'll see that so all the
configurations we provide into the
persistence unit and in springb what is
the persistence unit application do
properties so from that persistence unit
whenever you are starting an application
spring framework use that persistence
unit means application. properties and
it create an object of entity manager
Factory okay it creates an object of
entity manager Factory so you can say
that this is in configuration format
like application. properties it converts
into Java
object okay and populate the fields and
that object is known as entity manager
Factory now this entity manager Factory
use is to create entity
manager okay so before I go to entity
manager understand the relation between
persistence unit and entity entity
manager Factory for there can be
multiple persistence unit persistence
unit when I say that multiple
configuration for the
DB okay like what is the DB connection
what is the dialect what is the driver
and Etc okay so for one persistence unit
you have one object of entity manager
Factory if you have more than one
persistent unit the equivalent number of
factory would be created for example you
have 2
DB let's say I have one S2 and one is my
SQL my application connects to both
let's say so for this also I have one
persistence
unit and for this also I have
one persistence unit okay generally when
we use application do
properties there are lot of automation
happens beneath which we which is
abstracted to us okay so whenever we are
using application do properties to
Define this DB connection dialect driver
everything spring boot considered that
we have only one DB in an
application but if your application has
more than 1 DB then we generally
advisable is don't use application.
properties use at the configuration
class and pro provide both the
persistence unit or configuration
properly and connect to a proper
DV okay so there can be more than than
one persistence unit present and for
each persistence unit we have to create
an entity manager Factory we will see
how okay now you have created The Entity
manager Factory it's a Java object which
has all the
information why it is used see it's the
name factory factory for What entity
manager so whenever you required an
entity manager
object it goes to the
factory and get one
but what is entity manager entity
manager you can say that it's a
session in hibernate it's generally
known as session and in jpa terms it
call as entity manager so in entity
manager is the one where we have uh like
you can say that expose an API like we
provided right jpa repository above we
saw jpa repository provided like uh save
method find
all and what else it provide find by ID
so many
thing okay and uh jpa
repository if you see its
implementation internally it connects
with entity
manager okay entity manager also has
many methods like
persist okay so Pur is used for save for
find it might have something something
let's say query uh we can check but I
think it's query so if you are calling
save method for the jpa internally it
call entity manager.
persist okay so entity manager is
nothing provides an interface where we
have all the apis which is used to
insert query everything okay jpa
repository is just a wrapper above it I
I will tell you why the we we need
rapper or if we want we can directly
connect to the entity manager also
so somebody has to provide an
implementation right so who provide the
implementation for this jpa interface
Pur query it's your hibernate so
generally in hibernate there is a class
called
session so session IML provides an
implementation for each person each
query like if you want to
fetch there is a proper implementation
for it if you want to purchase there's a
proper implementation for it okay so in
simple terms whenever you have to
interact with the DB you want to
purchase you want to fetch you need an
entity manager object okay no matter
even if you're doing jpa repository
because internally JP repository you are
calling save internally it required
entity manager object only to call the
underlying jpa method so these are the
actual jpa
interface okay so whenever you want to
interact with the DB for persisting and
fetching you need entity manager object
and who helps to create an entity
manager object that is entity manager
Factory and if you see this it is one to
many relationship means for every
operation you need possible that you
require many entity manager objects okay
it's
possible okay so we might be creating
multiple entity manager
objects and each entity manager object
creates a persistence context okay so
consider persistence context is like
this so you create
a entity manager object and this entity
manager this is persistence context
this holds the entity so as from the
name it's a entity manager the manager
who manages the
entity now let's say that I want to
update user entity user entity okay I
want to do persist I want to insert so I
created new user
entity I created one object of new user
entity let's say obj object now I want
want to persist into the DB I
want entity manager object right entity
man I let's say I got an entity manager
object I call persist and I pass this
user
object so now here if you
see whenever you are
persisting right ultimately whatever the
objects which this entity manager is
working
on is stored here in inside a
persistence
context okay so persistence context you
can say that it's a placeholder for
entities whatever the entity manager is
working on so now let's say that you
have done get user from DB let's say
okay and
id1 so you got it what you need
definitely you need entity manager
object you call entity manager and let's
say you got uh let's say we check the
method let's say you call get method say
get me the user detail which has
id1 now you got an
object so using this entity manager you
got an object so where this object is
stored it is stored in the entity
manager persistence context okay so you
have an entity manager you have a
persistence context and there you have
object okay which is id1 one now you can
update here you can update this let's
say from uh name was XY Z you change the
name to ABC so everything is happening
inside a persistent context so
persistent context is nothing but a
placeholder for an entity okay once you
once you get it from the DB okay as soon
as the entity manager got the hold of
your entity it is stored inside this
persistence context and then you can
work on top of it and from there either
you can store into the
DB okay and you can uh remove it
itself so I will tell you the entity
life cycle also but to understand this
uh flow consider that for every entity
manager there is a persist uh
persistence context and this persistence
context Only Stores The Entity which
entity manager is working on so maybe
entity manager is updating three entity
user user details order
details invoice details let's say Okay I
want to purchase this I so I'm using
same entity manager object the same
entity manager object I am persisting
user detail I am persisting this I am
persisting this or I updating this so
somebody is holding this objects right
where I have to like if I am working on
this so I have fed from DB I now update
doing some updation it's not there in
the DB yet but I in memory I'm doing it
so somebody is storing this right object
yes entity manager restores it but we
are inside a persistence context
object
okay and if you remember from the first
uh I told you right why there uh there
was only insert call there was no select
query happen I told you first level
caching happened so this persistence
context helps
into first level caching too how I will
explain in depth but this also helps in
the first level caching because it only
stores The
Entity even though it's not there it's
there in the DB but it's uh you are
working in memory you are updating it so
pist context hold it for the entity
manager Okay so entity
manager whenever you have to interact
with a DB you need one entity manager
object and for each entity manager
persistence context is created and
through which holds the entity and once
it is done ultimately D comes into the
picture and what is dialect is so I told
you right earlier uh jdbc is the
underlying framework okay it works with
SQL
now or comes into the picture in
mid and jdbc doesn't understand the OM
language maybe jql or hql so somebody
need to translate that into SQL so that
dialect helps into
that okay so dialect is like uh from
this diagram you can get to know
that hibernate talks to jdbc but jdbc
only understand SQL and hnet works in
either jql let's say or or hql so
somebody needs to do some translation
right that's where the dialect comes
into the
picture and you can ask me right hey
Shan like in the application draw
properties we haven't defined any
dialect I told you right whenever we are
using application. properties we are
assuming that only one DB we are
connecting to Only One DB and there are
lot of Auto configuration happens so
springbot automatically picks proper
dialect for us but if we are not using
application do properties and we are
using at the rate configuration class
then we have to Define
everything okay ultimately dial comes
into the picture dial talks to jdbc and
ultimately jdbc talks to
DB1 so we have to see each and
everything properly
but let's
start first thing is p add your
dependency
okay and this will bring HB dependency
to then let's see persistence unit
first so it's what it's a logical
grouping of entity classes which share
same
configurations okay so persistence unit
means let's say I have 100 entities I
have 100 entities entity one entity 2
entity 100 so let's say this one to
entity 40 shares the same configuration
means they they want to go into the same
DB let's say
S2 now entity 41 to 100 are sharing the
same configuration they have to go
inside my SQL let's
say okay so what we do is one
persistence unit means logical grouping
of entities which share same
configuration so we can have one
persistence unit for this one
persistence unit for this
so if you're not using a spring boot
generally you create a persistence.xml
file like this so you create a
persistance unit you provide some name
here you provide a transaction type we
will see what is this transaction type
resource local means 1 DB transaction is
Scopes to 1 DB so from the previous
transaction uh video you know that right
whenever we create a transaction begin
commit its scope is specific to 1 DB
only
DB1 okay if you have more than one DB
db2 the same transaction transaction one
will not work okay it can scope to only
local to 1 DB so generally that is
resource unor local if you want
transaction to scope to multiple DB we
have to use
JTA not resource Loc but we will see
later so we will uh type what is the
transaction type we will group all the
entities which you want which is going
to share the below configuration so
let's say I have created two entities
sample entity one sample entity two so
this is like a
grouping then what is the provider I
want to use so here I want to use
hibernate provider you can even use
Eclipse link uh open jpa like this
currently I'm telling you if you're not
using springboard you have to Define
like this and the properties properties
like what is the dialect what is the
driver DB username password like this
but in Spring boot we don't create
persistent.
XML if you have only one DB one
application One DB you can use
application.
properties inside this you have already
seen how we can create data source we
can create DB driver user us name
password okay and here generally if you
see this is optional we haven't defined
previously okay but you can provide a
package to scan so it will this all
entities which is in this package it
will
scan okay but generally this is not
required because spring Bo look for all
atate entity
annotation so you don't have to provide
a specifically provide a package okay
then this is also not mandatory that you
don't have to provide what is the
hibernate provider what is the jpa
provider you are
using if you want you can specifically
provide hibernate persistence provider
if you want to override it but if you
don't provide it it will automatically
use this similarly what is the dialect
you want to use provide a proper dialect
okay uh dialect you already know what is
used for converting the jql or hql into
the s
but if this is also an optional because
if you don't provide it spring boot
automatically pick uh appropriately and
similarly you don't have to provide
transaction type this is the default it
would pick until unless you want to
override with J uh
JTA so resource local is uh whenever you
create a transaction begin commit it's
always the scope is to 1 DB
only okay so that's why we haven't we
only Define this we didn't Define all
these things the spring would
automatically take care of all these
things okay and always remember that
application. properties means only one
persistence you can have means Only One
DB
okay now let's see that entity manager
Factory you can also say that herey what
if I want more than one persistence file
in Spring boot how to created I will
show
you with this one example I will show
you now the second comes into the uh
architecture is after the persistence is
entity manager
Factory so using persistence unit
configuration or you can say that using
application. properties configuration
entity manager Factory object get
created during application startup
itself if any property is not provided
default one is picked and
set one entity manager is for one
persistence unit this class act as a
factory to create an object of entity
manager I have already explained entity
manager
Factory so here if you say this is the
class when you start an application
debug point in this class in this method
okay so the control will come here there
you will see that from the persistence
unit it is creating the entity manager
object Factory object
okay and if you say that hey what if we
want to manually create an object of
entity manager Factory I don't want this
spring framework So currently see this
spring framework is creating so spring
framework will reading from application.
properties and from application.
properties whatever the properties you
have provided it creates into one only
one persistence unit and from that it
creates an entity manager Factory
but if I want to take the whole control
how I can do it that I create one at
theate configuration let's say I call it
app config one okay in that one now you
know that whenever you are creating a
configuration now spring Auto
configuration not comes into the picture
you have to provide everything so you
have to first provide your data
source driver name jdbc username
password like we were already seen this
in the jdbc like what all things are
required for
connection once you have a data source
you need also one bean for jpa vendor so
I am creating a hibernate jpa vendor and
what is the dialect I want to use so you
provide
here and the third is like create a
object for this Factory so I created
this entity manager Factory there I am
setting this data data source like data
source and jpa vendor which I created
here this is the data source and this is
the jpa data vendor the same I mentioned
here so I set the data source I set the
J vendor what is the package you want to
scan and any unique name you can give to
your entity manager Factory now here if
you see I created the object not a
spring Boot and here application.
properties is not
present I am using at theate
configuration if you want to create
another persistence unit you can write
another
configuration and app config let's say
two or give proper name let's say my SQL
config let's say this is S2 config class
name and you can provide its proper data
source its vendor and then you can
create an entity manager
Factory okay so you can create as many
entity manager Factory for each
persistence unit all these
configurations considered as a
persistence
unit
okay so now till now we have created an
object now one more thing the
transaction
manager now you are saying that hey Shan
why transaction manager coming into the
picture and how it is associated with
entity manager Factory so for each
entity manager Factory you know that you
have a DB let's say
S2 my
SQL we have one persistence unit we have
one entity manager Factory we have one
persistence unit we have entity manager
Factory and now there come one more
transaction manager one transaction
manager for S2 one transaction manager
for
MySQL
okay now this transaction manager when
we are saying one transaction manager
for S2 one transaction manager for my
SQL it's like
resource local we are using whatever the
transaction this will
generate okay we have we are getting an
object of a transaction then we are
doing begin commit all this transaction
is scope is to this DB only whatever the
transaction is generated by this
transaction
manager then you do begin and commit
it's a scope is to this MySQL DB
only but if you use JTA
then it's like persistence unit entity
manager Factory persistence unit entity
manager Factory then you have let's say
uh S2 DB you have my SQL but you want
one transaction
manager okay that's what JTA
does okay so JTA has a scope of multiple
DB whatever you have registered the ENT
entity manager Factory for S2 and for
MySQL so it can take care of the
transaction for those span across
multiple DB but if you want to use
resource local so those no matter how
many persistence unit to have they have
a specific transaction
manager so during persistence unit we
have specified the value of transaction
type resource local or JTA so if you
don't provide in application do
Properties by by default it will use
resource local this is the by default
spring boot
uses if you want to use something else
like JTA you can override
it so it is of two type one is which
managing the transaction for One DB
another is which managing the
transaction which can span across
multiple DBS like what if you remember
from the high level design playlist
two-phase commit so JTA does internally
two-phase commit only
so here I will show you during
application startup only after entity
manager Factory object created now B
based on this app transaction type
resource local or JTA transaction
manager object is created one entity
manager Factory one transaction manager
is created so here if this see this one
transaction manager for managing
transaction for 1db so in the
application do properties here if you
see
I have
provided resource
local so now when you start an
application right the control goes here
into the jpa transaction manager now if
you remember from my transactional video
you know this hierarchy of the
transaction right jpa transaction
manager comes here so here if you see
this jpa transaction so there are two
jpa and JTA transaction
manager okay so currently if you using
resource local if you are using resource
local it creates an object of jpa
transaction
manager which is a specific transaction
is specific to 1
DB okay and we can also manually do it
now you already know how to manually you
have to create one configuration class
you need data source uh which vendor
hibernate vendor you create an entity
manager Factory and after the entity
manager Factory object you have to
create one more Bean for jpa transaction
manager you create a new object and you
pass the factory object so from this
Factory because this Factory has
everything what DB need to connect and
everything which is required for the
transaction manager because transaction
manager is directly associated with your
DB transaction manager is directly
associated with DB so it knows what DB
it need to connect
to okay okay and the use case two is the
transaction manager for creating
transaction which can span across
multiple DV so that's where the JTA
comes into the picture so I will no not
go JT at this time because it's again a
big topic I have to cover many like at
me cost ex data source okay and then
two-phase commit I also have to little
explain so it will out of the context
for this one but at this point we can
understand that transaction manager is
created also and it has one toone
relationship with the entity manager
Factory okay and this is based on your
persistence file only application.
properties so all the above steps happen
during application startup itself so now
let's say
that I have application. properties
right now let me put
into debugger Point here into entity
manager Factory is I'm starting an
application so here if you see the first
control comes here from to this creation
of entity manager Factory so it is
getting created from this persistence
unit info whatever we have provided in
application of properties from that
entity manager Factory is getting
created after that here if you see the
control comes to jpa transaction manager
and based on this entity manager Factory
it is trying to find find the entity
manager Factory here if you see right
based on the persistence unit and it
will create an entity manager which is
jpa transaction
manager and after that your application
is
started okay so whatever we have seen
till now it's till before the
application start up like before the
application got start up so we have
understand what is persistence unit what
is entity manager Factory and what is
also transaction manager comes into the
picture now your application is started
now here comes the usage of entity
manager and persistence context very
important so entity manager is what it's
an
interface in jpa that provide methods to
perform crud operation on entities it
just providing methods purist merge find
remove create query so purchase is for
saving merge is for updating find is for
fetching remove is for deleting create
queries for executing JPL queries we see
entity manager so entity manager is
nothing but an
interface this entity manager has all
this methods abstract methods like no
definition it's an interface right
remove
find find there are different ways
through which you can interact with the
DB and who provides the implementation
for
it so here if you see
hibernate so this session IML in
hibernate you can say that entity
manager is called a session so it's like
a implementation is provided by
hibernate if you are using open jpa you
will see something other class which is
providing the implementation for
your entity managers methods
and also if you see our repository which
we created here if you see whenever we
were calling let's say save whenever we
were doing save
internally it is connecting to entity
manager
only so you can ask right hey then why
we are interacting with jpa repository
why we can't directly interact with the
entity manager yes we can do that but
jpa repository you can say that provide
certain extra benefits like it has some
predefined method like find all delete
all there you don't have an um entity
manager you might have to use some uh
some business logic you have to add like
list of IDs you might have to send
something there in the jpa repository we
have pag generation and sorting
capability if you are directly using
enti entity manager you have to build
those capability and also if you see
that uh there are certain methods like
in insert modify delete for these
operation entity manager required at
theate
transaction so this is must if you don't
provide at the rate transaction for
these operation entity manager will
block it it will throw an exception so
entity uh jpa repository automatically
adds it up so here if you see that in
the jpa repository if I am uh calling
save
so inside save it automatically call at
theate transaction before calling purist
like an insert so you don't have to
worry about it okay and start and close
of entity manager so we also don't have
to no need to manage it like hey I have
created an entity manager do I need to
close it or do I have to keep it open
you don't have to worry about it if it
is required to close it it will close it
if it is not it will not close it so you
don't have to worry about managing of
entity manager because you're not
directly interacting with entity manager
now so there are many business logic
which is kept inside jpa
repository okay so one thing is you
clear that this is the actual jpa you
can say that interface to interacting
with the
DB okay or I would not say that directly
to the DB you can say that it is like
for persisting merge find internally it
is imple implemented by your provider
like hibernate
their hibernate provide a logic which
ultimately talks to
jdbc and ultimately data is stored to DB
so if I call it these are the actual
methods jpa provide through which you
can interact with the DB but internally
you know that what happening goes to
hiate implementation provides
implementation do a dialect then goes to
jdbc and then DB okay but now these are
abstracted to us these are all
abstracted to us for us if you want to
insert we have to call
okay entity manager interface methods
are implemented by jpa vendor like
hibernate entity manager Factory helps
to create an object of entity
manager okay so considered entity
manager is like without this you cannot
interact with the DB if you have the
object of this then only you can
interact and when you have an object of
this means you have created created one
session you have created one session and
that's why you can interact with DB
that's also we can say that's why in
hibernate it is known as
session create a session means you are
creating an object of entity
manager which now you created one
session with your DB now you can
interact it and if you close the session
means you're closing the entity manager
now you can't interact with the DP
that's simple as it is
and persistence context I told you right
considered it as a first level
cache for each entity manager
persistence context object is
created which hold the list of entities
it's working on and during the start
itself I explained you this it also
manage the life cycle of an
entity so here if you see entity manager
insert update delete operation are
transaction bounded I told you it first
check if transaction is open if not it
will throw
exception like but read operations are
not transaction bounded okay only insert
update delete and like other so here
take an example okay so I have created
one simple service class which is
interacting with user repository so here
user repository
here this is it is interacting with and
you know that internally jpa repository
I show that all insert update methods
are annotated with
transactional so this is now save method
which comes here this is the save method
internally there is an implementation
for Save method which comes here so here
it has automatically annotated with
transaction so you don't have to worry
about putting this what if I directly
call entity
manager okay instead of a spring
framework so how you will do it now
let's say that in service instead of my
repository I am creating a entity
manager so generally entity manager if
you're creating it your generally it use
like a persistence context
annotation it is like uh persistence
context like there is uh it is all to do
autowire but internally some business
logic like some validation
so now if you try to call entity
manager.
purist okay what would would happen is
it will throw a validation that
transaction required exception there is
no transaction so if you go to this uh
The annotation Interceptor it will
autowire this entity manager object plus
it has some business logic where it will
check the validation that
hey is there any transaction open if no
entity manager will
fail but what if I add theate
transaction at top of
it it work
properly okay so that's why I told you
that we generally use jpa repository
because it has lot of business logic
inherited we don't have to work those
business logic if you're directly
dealing with entity manager there are
lot of things you might have to consider
consider also and there might not be the
methods which are available like
pagination sorting and also the uh batch
method like find all get all delete all
all those
things and also I'll tell you a life
cycle of entity in persistence context
so now you already know that whenever we
are creating an entity manager object we
will see when entity manager object is
created and all but remember that
whenever entity manager object is
created internally it create a
persistence context
also now this entity manager you are
trying to let's say persist entity one
persist entity 2 some
modify entity 3 so you working on three
entities so it put a placeholder for
entity one its object entity two its
object ntity 3 its object okay and on
time to time it will purs to DB whenever
required till you are working it and not
updating into the DB it's there into the
persistence
context so this is the life cycle of an
entity inside a persistence context so
whenever you are creating a new
object so there are two
ways an object can go inside a
persistence context one
is this is the first way you are
creating a new object
so when you created a new user
entity it's it's called a transient
state or New
State whenever you want to persist into
the DB you want a entity manager object
and you call
persist now it first goes
into persistence
context it don't it don't directly goes
to DB right from entity manager purs
this don't directly go here it first
create a persistence context for this
entity manager put this here so means it
is now first goes to manage stage now
here means it is inside a persistence
context
object and from there ultimately it goes
to the DB that is one way so persistent
Contex still has
it so whenever any get query happens you
know right whenever get query happens
get you know right it that's that's why
it first you call get method of
transaction
manager it don't directly goes to the DB
it first goes to persistent manager so
persistent manager know that hey do I
have this am am I managing this object
uh uh entity if yes and it is valid it
will return it will not goes to the DV
so you know right persistent context is
also help in first level caching that I
will tell you in depth um but here
consider that the first way is to insert
into the purch Contex is create a new
object which is in transition state and
then your first time persisting it it
got added into the persistence context
and then ultimately goes to the
DB the second way is data is already
present into the DB and then you are
doing get get me one hey entity
manager dot get query 1 now persistent
man persistent contact doesn't have the
entity so it has uh data is present here
so it will first fetch it and then put
it inside it this is the second way
through which data can comes into the
persistent context manage which is
called say that manage State now
persistent context is managing
it okay after that you can let's say
remove it you want to delete from the DB
But ultimately it's not uh you want to
ultimately delete from DB but currently
it's not persisted so it can go to
remove the state so you call the remove
method entity manager. remove so what it
will do is it will change the state of
from this managed to removed but DB it
is might be still active because it is
not pushed to DB yet and when it
ultimately do
flush internally then actually it get
persisted that
removed okay
but there are chance that before you do
flush if you want to take it back you
can again move it to manage State
through again call purist on
it okay so maybe you call remove but you
change your mind you want it back you
can change this back to the manage State
ultimately DB will only get updated when
you have internally it called flush and
then all the changes into the
persistence context it will sync up with
the
DB also if let's say you have a
persistence context now you detach it
you don't want your entity to be managed
by persistence contact you can detach it
manually or you can close the entity
manager itself entity manager do close
whenever you do c close this entity get
removed what user entity get removed
from here now it is
detached now it is your responsibility
to sync it with the DB it's not
responsibility of the jpa to insert into
the
DB once you detach it means you are
taking the responsibility that for this
entity I will take care of
responsibility I will manage it but till
it is in manage uh State jpa your
persistent cont is managing it it will
take care of properly sinking to DB time
to time
and after detaching if you want to put
it you can call merge and it will again
goes back to control of a jpa and it is
in state
managed okay so from removed also state
it is possible to goes to detach State
like you can close it close the entity
manager
itself so you can know that this uh
entity goes to various States inside a
persistence cont context so that's why
we say that the persistent context
manages the life cycle of an entity so
it will keep it and uh you perform
operation on it and it will update the
DB like this okay okay so I hope that
with this you would be able to set up
jpa you would be able to run one flow
and while running the flow you at least
know how it is running
internally okay now now we will go with
the part three of jpa which is like
first level of caching see you soon bye